lovelzy残天  制作
(MAN SPEAKING RUSSIAN
OVER MEGAPHONE)
俄罗斯当局今天准备应付民众
The authorities in Russia are bracing themselves today
针对前亿万富翁尤里·科马洛夫
for mass protests against the trial
开庭一事的大规模抗议
of former billionaire Yuri Komarov.
目前俄罗斯公众
The case against Mr. Komarov
对尤里·科马洛夫一案存在着巨大的意见分歧
has caused widespread division amongst the Russian public,
有一部分人认为 他被判刑是国防部长候选人
some of whom view his incarceration as a political maneuver
也就是这个人
orchestrated by this man,
维克多·查克林操纵的政治手段
defense minister candidate Viktor Chagarin.
有何贵干 维克多
What do you want Viktor?
(DOOR CLOSES)
你挺有闲情雅致的嘛
Why are you doing this?
明天你准备怎么办
What do you want to accomplish tomorrow?
我准备为自己赎罪
I'm prepared to pay for my sins.
你也应该准备好
You should prepare yourself too.
Yuri ,
理智一点吧 我们曾经是朋友
let's be civil about this. We were friends once...
也可以再次成为朋友
...we could be again.
只要把文件交给我
Just give me the file...
你就可以重回以往的生活轨道
...and I'll hand your life back to you.
也会忘了这次愚蠢的审判
Forget this stupid trial.
我并不留恋以前的生活
I don't want my life back.
你以为我会让你明天在法庭上开口吗
You think I'm going to let you talk tomorrow?
没有人会听到你的声音
No one is going to hear you!
法庭里都是我的人
I own everybody in that courtroom.
除了我
You don't own me.
Mike.
查克林要对科马洛夫动手了
Chagarin's making a move on Komarov.
见鬼 找那边的人处理
Shit. I'll see if we got local.
我们准备好了 开始吧
We are ready to get started.
打电话吧
Make the call.
你不会让我失望吧
You won't disappoint me?
我什么时候让你失望过
Have I ever disappointed you?
Anton .
(CELLPHONE DIALING)
埃里克 我是维克多
Alik, it's Viktor.
尤里·科马洛夫向你问好
Yuri Komarov says hello...
是时候抓他了
It's time to grab him.
尤里·科马洛夫
Yuri Komarov?
以及 告别
...and GOODBYE.
(ALL SCREAMING)
(GUNFIRE)
麦克莱恩
McClane.
你好 墨菲
Hey, Murph, how you doing?
很准嘛 老爹
Nice grouping, Grandpa.
是啊 还不赖
Yeah, not bad.
就这个
Is that it?
对 找到他了
Yep. We found him.
不过不太妙
It's not good, John.
医院还是太平间
Hospital or morgue?
更糟
Worse.
你们最后一次联系是什么时候
When was the last time you spoke to this kid?
有一阵了
It's been a while.
大概有好几年了
Maybe a few years, even.
我们上次见面 很不愉快
Last time I saw him, it was pretty ugly.
这里面 有好几种说法
Well, there's a few different versions in there,
不过 我的人确定 他被关在莫斯科一所监狱里
but my people are pretty sure he's being held at a Moscow prison
在等候宣判
awaiting sentencing.
什么罪名
What's he charged with?
多了去了
It's a nasty sheet.
能判无期就算走运了
He'll be lucky to get life.
那小子就会惹麻烦
He can never get out of his own way.
一身臭毛病
He had a lot of problems
可毕竟是我儿子
He's still my kid.
我知道
I know.
可那是俄罗斯,他们有他们的做法
But it's Russia.They do things differently over there.
我也是
Me, too.
(CHUCKLES)
祝你好运 老爹
Good luck, Poppy.
谢了 小子
Thanks, kid.
(SHOUTING)
God damn you ! God damn it!
(DROPS GUN)
欢迎来到肯尼迪国际机场
Welcome to John F. Kennedy International Airport.
Thanks, kid .
McClane, 祝你好运
McClane, Good luck.
See you soon .
(DOOR OPENS)
(LIGHTER FLICKS)
(CIGARETTE SIZZLES)
(EXHALES)
听说你有东西要交给我
I was told you had something to offer me?
你在寻找尤里·科马洛夫的犯罪证据
You're looking for evidence against Yuri Komarov?
也许
Perhaps.
带我和他一起上法庭
Put me in the courtroom with him...
我可以指证是他雇我谋杀安东
...and I'll testify that Komarov hired me to murder Anton.
是吗
Did he?
我可以宣誓作证
I'll testify under oath.
这样做够了吗
That's good enough, isn't it?
(DJ CHATTERING IN RUSSIAN
ON RADIO)
(STAMMERING IN BROKEN RUSSIAN)
大干四哥法院
...Draganskiy courthouse?
你会说俄语
You speak Russian?
说得还行吗
How did I do?
喔 你说要买一大袋头发
Well, you asked for a large bag of hair
带去塔干斯卡亚法院
on the way to Taganskaya courthouse.
不过 我听懂了 听懂了
But I got it. I got it.
好
Good.
这里也老堵吗
Traffic sucks here, too, huh?
赌？
Sex?
你想赌博 想找赌场
You want sex? Sexy clubs?
不 不是赌博
No. No sex.
我是说这里车很堵
It sucks, this traffic.
出事故了
What is it? An accident?
没有
No.
这条路叫花园环路 一直很堵
Garden Ring. Is bad.
每天都很堵
Always traffic, always traffic.
你是美国人
You're American?
对 美国人 纽约来的
Yeah, American. New York.
大苹果城
The Big Apple.
我想从这座不夜城中慢慢醒来
# I want to wake up in that city that never sleeps #
对 没错
That's it.
法兰克·辛纳屈 大家都叫他董事长
Frank Sinatra. Chairman of the Board.
对
That's right.
董事长 对
The Chairman. Yeah.
你 你唱得很棒
You sing good.
这些小城的忧郁 在渐渐融化
# These little town blues are melting away #
是的 我爱唱歌
Yes, I sing.
我从早唱到晚
I sing all the time.
是吗
Yeah.
山之王 世界之巅
# King of the hill Top of the world #
呃
Huh?
高山 是高山之巅
Heap. "Top of the heap."
好吧 好吧 塔加斯卡亚法院 就在那儿
All right, all right. Taganskaya courthouse, right there.
过两个街区
Two blocks.
你还是走路吧 车太堵了 实在太堵
You better walk, traffic is bad. Really bad.
多少钱
What do I owe you?
嗨 不要钱
Hey, no money.
不要钱 你都让我唱歌了 你让我唱歌
No money, you let me sing. You let me sing.
你刚才还听我唱歌 不要钱了
You listen to my singing. No money.
欢迎你来到莫斯科
Welcome to Moscow.
这些小城的忧郁 在渐渐融化
# That little town blues are melting away #
我将有一个全新的开始
# I'm gonna make a brand new start of it #
在陈旧的纽约
# In old New York #
(SIREN WAILING)
莫斯科市中心的抗议
...protests in central Moscow,
已经蔓延到了俄罗斯全国
following a day of demonstrations in Russia.
The unrest comes as authorities have been
accused of fraud
throughout the country's elections.
FEMALE REPORTER:
. . .some pictures
out of Russia right now.
Protests happening there.
This is a look
at the demonstration.
(BIRDS SCREECHING)
(SIREN WAILING)
(PROTESTERS CHANTING)
(PROTESTERS YELLING)
(DOOR OPENS)
(CROWD CHATTERING)
(JUDGE BANGING GAVEL)
肃静
Quiet!
遵守法庭秩序
Order in the courtroom!
(GAVEL BANGING CONTINUES)
遵守法庭秩序
Order in the courtroom!
秩序
Order!
关上大门
Seal the doors!
(CLOCK TICKING)
( INDISTINCT)
引爆器
Detonator.
可是 那些司机
But, sir... the drivers?
给我引爆器
Detonator.
会很响哦
It's gonna be loud.
(GRUNTS)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
嗨
Hey!
(ALARM RINGING)
(PANTING)
(YELLING IN RUSSIAN)
快点 快点
Come on, come on!
快走
Come on now!
走 走
Come, come.
走
Come!
羁押室
The cage.
检查羁押室
Check the cage.
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
(MAN SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
(GRUNTS)
他们不在里面
They are not here.
上当了
No kidding.
(SIREN WAILING)
发生什么事了
What's happening?
科马洛夫要活的
Take Komarov alive...
其他人要死的
...kill the other one.
是
Yes.
埃里克
Alik.
我们需要那份文件
We need this file.
穿上这个
Put that on!
你是谁
Who are you?
你最好的朋友
Your best friend.
(TIRES SCREECH)
杰克
Jack!
爸爸
Dad?
快下车
Get out of the van!
你来干什么
What are you doing here?
杰克 嗨
Jack! Hey!
杰克
Jack
见鬼
Shit.
科马洛夫 科马洛夫
Komarov! Komarov!
快 上卡车
Quick... get the truck!
你快回家
Go home.
你到底在干嘛 杰克
What the fuck do you think...? Jack!
这事你对付不了
You're out of your depth, John.
杰克 你在干嘛
Jack! What are you doing?
不 不
No! No!
我们要抓活的
We need him alive!
杰克
Jack!
你要杀了我
You're gonna shoot me?
你要开枪打你老爸
You're gonna shoot your own father?
你不该来的
You shouldn't be here, John.
你不该来
You shouldn't be here.
你想干嘛
What are you doing?
杰克
Jack!
噢
Whoa!
你这笨蛋想压死我吗
You're gonna fucking run over me?
你只会把事情搞得更糟
You're only making it worse!
Jack.
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
给我让开
Get out of the way!
有种报警啊
Call a cop!
(TIRES SCREECH)
(HORNS HONKING)
Come on , go !
(MAN YELLS)
Idiot.
死神1号 610呼叫死神1号
Reaper One? Reaper One from 6-1-0.
他在谁手上
Who's got him?
时间紧迫 福克西
Clock's running. Foxy.
锁定目标 显示图像
On the paper now. Box on.
- 收到 - 显示图像
- Copy that. Box on. - Okay, here we go.
MAN : Okay, here we go.
61 这是死神 收到 请说
6-1, Reaper, we read you. Go ahead.
我们情况怎么样
Reaper, how are we looking?
你们延迟了
Your guy is late.
那家伙的速度太慢了
His rate of progress is way off.
任务时间追加6分钟
MET now plus 6 minutes.
作战如此滞后 追加6分钟
MCC Reaper. MET now plus 6.
不该这样的 真是难以置信
This is un-frigging-believable.
作战如此滞后
MCC Reaper. That's not how it works.
不对劲 我认识这个人 他不会这样
Something's off. I know this guy. This doesn't happen.
死神 61准备好了 待命
MCC Reaper, 6-1 is in the hole. Stand by.
61 请注意 你错过时机了
6-1, be advised, your window is closed.
停止攻击目标
Time on target is no-go.
重复 停止攻击目标
I say again, TOT is no-go.
死神 现在是实战 不是演习 收到吗
Reaper, this is real-world, not exercise, do you copy?
不行 长官 警方会封闭花园环路
No, sir, Moscow police will have shut down the Garden Ring.
死神 他来不及撤离
Reaper! He's no-go for extraction .
太晚了 终止行动 终止
It's too late. Shut it down. Pull it!
Pull it!
任务终止 死神撤退
6-1, mission window is closed. Reaper is out of here.
快点
Come on!
见鬼 该死
Shit!
给我接行动组
Get me Operations.
死神
Reaper!
通知迈克·考林斯
Get Mike Collins looped in.
实施B计划 去安全屋 快去
Tell him it's Plan B, safehouse. Go now!
B计划
Plan B. No choice.
见鬼
Shit.
任务终止 他们封锁了花园环路
It's blown. They shut the Garden Ring.
- 准备收割 大家继续 - 专心点 伙计们
- Harvest is in effect. - Keep on working.
福克西 我们去完成任务
Let's finish this, Foxy.
该死的麦克莱恩
Damn you, McClane!
都怪你
Damn you!
(HORN HONKING)
噢 见鬼
Oh, fuck!
杰克 我话还没说完呢
Jack! I'm not done talking to you!
他是谁
Who is this?
快开 快
Come on, go!
麻烦你专心点
Concentrate, please.
嗨 就这样 过来 对
That's right, come on through, yeah!
有本事撞我呀
See if you can hit this guy!
天呐
Jesus!
(MAN YELLING)
这家伙烦死了
I'm tired of this guy.
发射火箭弹 快
RPG now!
见鬼
Jesus!
你没打中 你小子是故意的吧
You missed! Interesting choice, man.
(CHUCKLES)
(GRUNTS)
嗨  嗨 停车
Hey, hey!
Hey!
Whoa !
Hey! Whoa !
(GROANING)
见鬼
Come on!
你在跟我开玩笑吗
You gotta be fucking kidding me!
(YELLING IN RUSSIAN)
什么
What?
(CONTINUES YELLING
IN RUSSIAN)
你以为我听得懂你说的话吗
Do you think I understand a word you're saying?
我的天呐
Jesus Christ.
没事吧 我很好 谢了
It's okay, I'm fine, thanks.
噢 伙计 你开车跟我奶奶一样慢
Oh, man, you're driving like my grandma!
我叫你开车 你得开得飞起来
When I say drive, I mean fly!
噢 哦
Oh, yeah!
快给我让开
Get out of the way!
噢 上帝保佑
Oh, God.
天呐
Jesus!
噢 真会挑时间
Oh, for the love of...
(WOMAN SCREAMS)
对不起 女士
Sorry, ma'am!
(HORNS BLARE)
对不起
Sorry!
(LAUGHING)
看见他手势吗
Did you see this guy?
Oh , man !
我来了
Knock knock.
Guess who!
我受够这混蛋了
I've had enough of this shit.
哦 伙计 嗨
Oh, man, hey!
就这两下 就这点本事
Is that it? Is that your best shot?
(INAUDIBLE)
该死的约翰
Damn you, John.
都怪你
Damn you!
(McCLANE COUGHING)
(CHATTERING IN RUSSIAN)
(SIREN WAILING)
(PEOPLE SCREAMING)
嗨 我在上面
Hey! Up here!
朝上面打
Shoot up here!
约翰 上车
John! Get in!
在我改主意前快上来 真是的
Get in before I change my mind. Jesus!
你就磨蹭吧
Take your time.
这到底是怎么回事 杰克
Jack, what the fuck was that, huh?
闭嘴 给我闭嘴 约翰
Shut up. Shut up, John.
我发誓这次我一定会开枪打你
I swear to God, I will put a bullet in you this time.
你以为你在跟谁说话
Who do you think you're talking to?
我最不想见到的人
The last person I want to see.
噢 是吗 但请问刚才是谁
Well, maybe you missed the whole part back there
把你和那个老头
where I saved you and Papa Geppetto here
从一帮俄罗斯恶棍手里救出来的
from a whole bunch of Russian bad guys.
你救我们 救我们
You saved? You saved?
没错 救你们
That's right, saved.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
- 闭嘴 - 闭嘴
- Shut up. - Shut up.
你是全世界最失败的人了
You're a world class screw-up, you know that, John?
我很失败 我很失败
I'm a screw-up? I'm a screw-up?
可我还是你老爸
I'm still your father.
是啊 这件事我没法改变
Yeah, nothing I can do about that.
真是可笑
What a joke.
给我闭嘴 别乱碰东西
Just shut up. Try not to touch anything, all right?
你破坏得够多了
You've done enough goddamn damage.
会见定在下个星期
The appointment is next week...
我们马上开始准备
We will begin immediately.
对不起 先生 科马洛夫跑了
Excuse me, sir. Komarov has escaped.
我待会儿打给你 科马洛夫出了问题
I'll call you back. There is a problem with Komarov.
怎么回事
What happened?
有人袭击了法院
Some sort of attack on the courthouse.
谁带走了他
Who took him?
他们还不知道
They don't know yet.
你说不知道是什么意思
What do you mean you don't know?
呃
Eh...
现场太混乱了
...well it's confusing...
有人看到科马洛夫
Eyewitnesses say they saw Komarov...
跟一个美国人跑了
...with an American.
美国人
What American?
约翰·麦克莱恩
John McClane.
快进来
Let's go.
你先请
After you.
对 他来了 对 我会处理
Yeah, I got him. Okay, I'm on it.
出了点意外 耽误了 对不起
Look, Mike, we had an unexpected delay. I'm sorry.
我明白
I understand.
我完全没想到会碰上他
This is the last guy on earth I expected to see.
听我说 尤里 莫斯科有一大群人在找你
Listen to me, Yuri, you have half of Moscow looking for you.
- 我要你把衣服换掉 - 带我来这儿干嘛
- I need you to get dressed. - Why am I here?
换衣服吧 相信我
Please put on these clothes. Trust me.
这是你手铐的钥匙 拿着
This is the key to your cuffs. Take these.
噢 我的老天爷
Oh, my Jesus.
- 你没事吧 - 什么
Are you okay? What?
你有查克林的文件吗
Do you have the file on Chagarin?
这就是你的工作
This is what you been doing, Jack?
狗屁间谍
Spy shit?
是这样吗
This is it?
(LAUGHING)
你是间谍 噢 天呐
You're a spy? Oh, my God.
新泽西州平原镇来的007
The 007 of Plainfield, New Jersey.
真有你的
Very nice.
麦克莱恩 闭嘴
McClane, shut up.
别激动 伙计
Take it easy, Oddjob.
我在度假
I'm on vacation.
你妈准会高兴
Your mom will be pleased.
我们还担心你吸毒呢
We thought you were doing drugs or something.
科马洛夫先生
Mr. Komarov.
或者贩毒 不过这是我猜的
Or selling drugs, but that was me, really.
你有查克林的那份文件吗
Do you have the file on Chagarin?
有还是没有
Yes, or no?
其实很简单
It's very simple, Yuri.
你给我文件 我带你离开俄罗斯
You give me the file, and I get you out of Russia.
你就自由了 怎么样
And you're a free man. What do you say?
我无所谓 我不在乎生死
It's not about me. I don't care about my life.
条件就这些
Well, that's the deal.
没别的选择
It's the only deal.
想清楚
Come on.
你想清楚 救救你自己
Come on, Yuri. Help yourself.
怎么样
What's it gonna be?
给还是不给
Yes or no?
时间不等人 快点
The clock is ticking, Yuri. Come on.
你们能带我出去
You will get me out of here?
就凭你们三个
Only the three of you?
喔 俄国佬 我跟他们不是一伙的
Whoa, Nijinsky. I'm not in the gang.
我刚下飞机 时差还没倒过来呢
I just got off the plane. I'm still jet-lagged.
我跟这事没关系 对吗 杰克
I'm not involved in this. Huh, Jack?
除非能带我女儿一起走
Only if I can take my daughter with me.
查克林的人会杀了她
Chagarin's people will kill her.
好的 不过要快
Fine. Make it quick.
呃
Ah.
文件在哪儿
Where's the file?
在普里皮亚季 不过钥匙在莫斯科
It's in a vault in Prypiat, but the key is here in Moscow.
在乌克兰酒店
At Hotel Ukraina.
见鬼
Shit!
打电话 我们去酒店 走吧
Make your call. We're going to the Ukraina, let's go.
(LINE RINGING)
我是爸爸
It's papa...
(DAUGHTER SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
我很好 宝贝
I'm fine, Sunshine...
我们晚点再细说
...we'll talk later.
听着
Listen.
我会在我和你妈妈第一次跳舞的地方等你
I'll be waiting for you where your mother and I shared our first dance.
现在就去
Now.
要快 要快 你明白吗
Hurry! Hurry! You understand?
(ENDS CALL)
听着 迈克 早上的事我很抱歉
Mike, listen, I'm sorry about this morning, man.
没关系
It's fine.
行了 走吧
Okay, let's go.
有敌人
Contact!
趴下 快趴下
Down! Get down!
快 快趴下 快 快 快
Go! Get down! Go, go, go!
(YELLING IN RUSSIAN)
约翰 掩护我
John, cover!
来啊 哥们儿
Come on, buddy!
快走 快走
Go! Go!
(BEEPING)
去死吧 混蛋
That's right, jerk-off!
行了 约翰 我们走
All right, let's move, John!
我在度假呢
I'm on fucking vacation!
快点 动作快点 小心头
Come on, time to hustle. Watch your head.
麦克莱恩 快走
McClane, move it.
大老远跑过来 这也太扯了
8,000 fucking miles for this?
低一点 尤里 再低点
Get down, Yuri. Stay low!
头低下
Head down.
快点 快走
Come on. Go, go!
(RAPID GUNFIRE)
什么破安全屋
Safe house, my ass.
他知道我们是老年人吗
He knows how old we are, no?
走吧
Come on.
过来
Here, here, here.
坐这儿 你没事的 别害怕
Sit down. You're all right.
让我看一下
Let me look at you.
不要紧 没事的 没事的
It's all right. You're fine.
你在干嘛
What are you doing?
杰克
Jack.
你冷静下来 尤里 你不会有事的
Calm down, Yuri, okay? You're gonna be just fine.
来 穿上这个 穿上这个 暖和一点
Here, put this on, stay warm.
这算什么 五分钟
What was that, John? Five minutes? Five minutes?
- 你用五分钟就毁了我们三年的行动 - 不用谢
- You blew a three-year op in five minutes! You're welcome!
别客气 我还能怎么办
You're welcome! What do you want me to do?
我怎么 这么倒霉
Unbelievable. Unbelievable.
我的身份暴露了 我在这儿一个朋友都没了
I'm so fucking burned. I got no friends in this town anymore.
你们中情局的人呢 联系他们
What about your people at Langley? Just give them a call.
手机给我
Give me your phone.
(PHONE SHATTERS)
我预付了两年的话费
It's a two-year contract on that phone.
那是什么 快给我
What are you carrying? Give me that.
行了 你有现金吗
All right. You got any cash on you?
有点儿美金
Some American money.
你们在磨蹭什么 我们得赶快走
What are you talking about? We need to keep on moving.
我们得给那家伙找个医生 帮他处理伤口 杰克
We have to get this guy to a doctor. To medical attention, Jack.
任务仍然有效
The mission stands.
你的任务都快流血过多而死了
Your mission is bleeding out over there.
继续执行任务 去酒店拿钥匙
The mission continues. We go to the hotel.
来吧 我们走 快走 快
Come on, let's move. Let's move.Come on
这也太扯了
This is nuts.
你现在要出去杀人
What, are you going to go out and kill somebody else now?
干嘛为一个人这么兴师动众
Why all this trouble for just one guy?
他是政治犯
He's a political prisoner.
约翰 虽然你不在乎
Not that you care, John,
可这关系到国家安全 懂吗
but it's a matter of national security, all right?
他有证据能扳倒查克林 我们需要他
He's got the goods to stop Viktor Chagarin, and we need that to happen.
噢 这样的话
Well, great, Jack.
送他去大使馆不就行了
Let's drop him off at the Embassy, and we can go home.
开什么玩笑 安全屋都出事了
Are you kidding me? After what happened at the safe house?
事情没那么简单
Look, it doesn't work like that, all right?
这是个外交烂摊子 我不过是炮灰
It's a huge diplomatic mess, and I'm a burnable asset.
我要拿到那份文件 才能完成任务
So, I now need that file to un-fuck this mission.
还有问题吗
Any more questions?
有 就一个
Yeah, just one.
为什么从来不告诉我你的下落
How come you never called and told me where you were?
好像你关心似的
Like you'd give a shit.
Shit.
Well , we're not going in the front door.
行了 慢点 慢点
All right, hold up, hold up.
好了 尤里 你听我说 就快搞定了 知道吗
Okay, Yuri, listen to me, all right? We're almost done.
我们一拿到钥匙 就去取文件
As soon as we get that key, we're gonna grab the file,
然后带你离开俄罗斯 懂吗
get you and your daughter out of Russia, all right?
好的
All right.
好的 听我说 你表现很好 挺住
Listen to me, you're doing good. All right?
再坚持一会儿 看着他 约翰
I need you to hang here a second.
Keep an eye on him, John.
嗨 嗨
Hey, hey.
唉 别一口一个约翰的 怎么不叫我爸爸
What is it with all this "John" shit?
Whatever happened to "Dad?"
问得好
Good question.
俄语里有个词形容他这种男人
In Russia, we have word for men like him.
柯鲁托伊
"Krutoi."
意思是 凶悍 顽强
It means "tough," "hard."
他这样的叫不良少年
In America, it means "juvenile delinquent."
你就这一个孩子
Is he your only child?
不 我还有个女儿
No. I got a daughter, too.
你呢
Y
我只有一个宝贝女儿
I have only my  Solnyschka.
她小的时候 我一直在忙工作
When she was little, I was working all the time.
我认为工作是最重要的
I believed work was all that mattered.
我也没好好照顾孩子
I screwed my kid's life up, too.
我没日没夜地工作
You work all the time
可警察没什么休息时间
around the clock most of the time, when you're a cop.
我那时觉得拼命工作是件 是件好事 对吗
I just thought that working all the time was a good thing, you know?
我完全没照顾到他
I didn't help him at all.
你还有机会
It's never too late,
但愿如此
I hope.
行了 我们走
Okay, let's go.
尤里 宴会厅在酒店的哪个区域
All right, Yuri, which part of the building is the ballroom in?
在主楼里
Main tower.
主楼的哪一层
Main tower. Which floor?
顶层
Top floor.
保安方面呢
What about security?
你记得保安 摄像头之类的吗
You remember any guards? Cameras? Anything like that?
我不知道
I don't know.
你 你得想起来
Well, I need you to remember.
我在牢里关了五年 怎么会记得
I was in prison for five years, how should I know?
可能都变了
Everything could have changed. I know.
是的 我知道 麻烦你好好回忆一下
Just think, all right? Picture it in your head.
宴会厅在89年关闭
The ballroom was closed in '89.
现在可能在重新施工
I think it's under construction now.
所以那层楼没保安
So that floor's unsecured.
我不知道 听着 我女儿在里面
I don't know! Listen! My daughter is in there.
我都害怕死了 快走吧
I'm scared to death, let's go!
冷静点 尤里
Just calm down, Yuri.
(BEEPS)
(ELEVATOR MUSIC PLAYING)
(ELEVATOR BELL RINGS)
你以前也这么干过吧
I guess you have done that before.
真聪明
Smart.
这我也会
I could have done it.
(ELEVATOR BELL RINGS)
伊莲娜
Irina?
爸爸
Papa.
- 伊莲娜 - 爸爸
- Irina. - Papa!
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
好感人呐
That's tender.
你也会感动
Really? I wouldn't know.
(SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
要拥抱吗
Need a hug?
我们家才不来这一套呢
We're not really a hugging family.
也是
That's right.
我们还需要拿一样东西
We just have to get one thing...
然后我们就离开莫斯科 远走高飞
...and then we're leaving Moscow for good.
好吗
OK?
好的
OK.
他们是什么人
Who are they?
年轻的那个是中情局的
The young one works for CIA.
年纪大的是他爸 他们是美国人
The old one is his father. Americans.
谢天谢地 幸亏有他们
Then thank God for them.
我感觉有点不太对劲儿
There's something no good about this.
闭嘴 行吗
Just shut up, all right?
说真的
I'm telling you, Jack,
这里有问题
this smells bad.
别说了 行吗
Just stop, okay?
听着 你可能没法理解这种状况 我知道
This might seem like a totally foreign concept, you know?
你喜欢硬闯 即兴发挥
I know you love to just run in, making shit up.
而我是专家 我有计划
But like any professional, I have a plan.
我们按计划行事 好吗
So let's just stick to it, okay?
听你的就是了
Just move your plan along.
行了 尤里 拿完钥匙就离开这儿
All right, Yuri, come on. Let's grab the key, get out of here.
好的
Yes.
一会儿就好
Just take a moment.
你好吗
How you doing?
很好
Fine.
你怎么这么快就到了
How did you get over here so quick?
我
Well...
我走花园环路来的
I took Garden Ring.
花园环路 那条路老是堵车 对吗
Oh, the Garden Ring. Supposed to always be bad, right?
(GRUNTS)
嗨 约翰
Hey, John.
来的时候堵车吗
Did you get stuck in traffic?
我拿到了 拿到了
I have it! I have it.
欢迎你们 美国佬
Welcome, Americans.
(GASPS)
快点把枪放下 混蛋
Put your goddamn guns down, asshole!
(SHUSHING)
爸爸 这是怎么回事
Papa, what is going on?
把武器交出来
Give me your weapons.
你过来拿
Come and get them.
(LAUGHS)
当真
Really?
Really.
爸爸
Papa.
尤里
Yuri.
放下武器
Do it.
我以为就你是问题少年
I thought you were a problem child.
专家 这就是你计划好的
This a part of your plan, Mr. Professional?
你这是干什么
What are you doing?
为了钱 爸爸
It's about money, papa...
几百万的美元
...millions of dollars.
你以为我的生活很轻松吗
You think life was easy for me?
在你被陷害入狱以后
While you were sitting in prison being a victim?
可我
But,
是你爸爸
I'm your father.
我是你女儿
And I am your daughter.
现在就杀了他吧
We should kill the old man now.
他还有用
We still need him.
你可以杀掉他们
But them you can kill.
- 谢谢 - 走吧
- Thank you.  let's go.
哈
Hi.
我的发音对不对
I don't know if I'm saying this right.
嗨
Hi.
知道我最讨厌美国人什么吗
Do you know what I hate about the Americans?
全都讨厌
Everything.
尤其是牛仔
Especially cowboys.
我本来想当一个 舞蹈演员
I could have been a dancer. I swear to God.
可没人支持我
But nobody supported me.
你们俩
You two
实在是
have been such a
太 令人 讨厌了
pain in the ass!
Come on , come on !
我更喜欢跳舞 真的
I prefer dancing, really.
不过杀人比在杂货店干活要过瘾多了
But killing is much, much better than working in a grocery shop!
我的天呐
Jesus Christ!
(LAUGHS)
打得好
Nice one.
(GRUNTS)
你们这些人 太自以为是了
You guys. So arrogant.
现在不是1986年了
It's not 1986, you know.
里根早死了
Reagan is dead.
(CHUCKLES)
(CHUCKLING CONTINUES)
对不起 噢 天呐
Sorry. Oh, God.
(CHUCKLES)
有什么好笑的
What's funny there?
没法说
Can't tell you.
我不是笑你 你们的衣服很棒
It's not you. I love these outfits.
人也长得帅气
You guys are looking good.
(ALL LAUGHING)
够了 谢谢
That was enough, thank you.
(LAUGHING STOPS)
来跳舞吧
Let's dance.
快点 快走
Come on! Come on!
(MEN YELLING IN RUSSIAN)
杰克
Jack!
记得上次你走之前我们聊过吗
Remember the last time we talked just before you went away?
噢  不 不 不
Oh, no! No, no!
别在我们临死前搞煽情
You're not gonna open up to me right before we die!
这不是你的风格 约翰
No, that's not your thing, John.
我的风格是什么
What's my thing?
干掉那些坏蛋 这才像你
Fucking killing bad guys, that's your thing!
你今天死不了
You're not gonna die today!
快走
Go!
见鬼
Shit!
该死的
Fuck.
没戏了 约翰
We're finished, John.
(CHATTERING IN RUSSIAN
ON RADIO)
l'm taking care of it now.
真不敢相信
can't believe this.
怎么会变成这样 见鬼
I can't believe this. This is unbelievable.
杰克 嗨
Jack. Hey!
我的天呐
Jesus!
快走
Come on!
快离开这儿
Let's get out of this building!
(McCLANE COUGHING)
他们在哪儿
Where are they?
走吧
Come on.
埃里克 完事了 搞定了
Alik, that's it. We're done!
我们走
Let's go!
左转弯
Break left!
收到 长官
Copy, Commander.
(SIRENS WAILING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
抓到他了吗
Do you have him?
是的
Yes.
那文件呢
And the file?
文件在他手上吗
Does he have it?
我需要那份文件 埃里克
I need that file, Alik.
他会带我们去拿
He's taking us to it.
不要再出差错了 埃里克
No more mistakes, Alik.
文件到手以后
And when you have the file...
把他们全干掉
...kill them both.
遵命
Yes, sir.
(COUGHING)
见鬼
Shit.
刚才真刺激
That was exciting.
是啊 很好玩
Yeah. Loads of fun.
再来一次
You wanna go again?
你中弹了
Are you shot?
没有 我没事
No, I'm fine.
让我看看
Let me take a look at that.
我没事
It's fine.
该死的
Oh, fuck.
她居然为了查克林出卖自己爸爸
I can't believe she betrayed her father for Chagarin.
我实在无法理解
I don't understand that.
你会理解的
Someday you will.
孩子嘛
Kids.
下一步呢
What's our next move?
不知道
I don't know.
你不知道 我不知道 行了吧
You don't know? I don't know, all right?
我彻底没招了 全都完了
I mean, I'm out of moves. I don't know.
我不知道
I don't know.
我搞砸了
I screwed up.
我毁了整个任务
I blew the mission.
那这里 没我们的事了 对吗
Well, then we're done, right?
对 没戏了
Yeah, we're done.
没戏了
We're done.
那我们就回家
We should just go home.
离开莫斯科前 我们先去一家药店
We'll stop by a little pharmacy on our way out of Moscow,
给你弄点 给你弄点消炎杀菌的药
get you some Merthiolate or mercury
处理一下你的小擦伤
and fix up your little scratches, here.
然后带你回家 买个玩具
Get you home. Get a little toy set.
喝一杯加了巧克力酱的热牛奶
Get yourself a nice warm glass of milk with a little Bosco in it.
穿上你的中情局拖鞋
Get your CIA slippers.
噢 行了
All right.
- 干嘛 - 我懂了
- What? - I get it.
你说怎么办
What the hell are we gonna do?
文件里有什么
What's in the file?
对查克林不利的证据
Evidence on Chagarin.
哪方面的证据
Evidence about what?
切尔诺贝利
Chernobyl.
是这样的
Look, listen to me.
科马洛夫和查克林
Komarov and Chagarin used to have this
他们以前 一起挣过非法的外快
nasty little side-racket going on back in the day.
他们偷偷抽取武器里的铀 因为贪心
They siphoned weapons-grade uranium, got greedy,
导致了核泄漏
caused the meltdown.
后来 他们就反目了
Then, you know, they fell out.
以前的搭档 现在是的冤家
Former partners, bad break-up.
这些人渣
Scumbags.
所以 查克林把科马洛夫弄进监狱
So, Chagarin had Komarov thrown in jail.
把他关起来 忘掉他
You know, put him in a hole, forget about him.
这样就不用担心了
Doesn't have to worry anymore.
那你们为什么要营救他
So what happened to rescuesque?
是吗 原来如此
Yeah, well, that figures.
查克林是个十足的恶棍 是危险分子
Listen, Chagarin is bad news. He's the real deal.
他要是掌了权 他们这个国家就完了
If we see this guy in control, we're gonna see the whole thing fall apart.
恐怖主义
I'm talking terrorism,
大规模杀伤性武器
WMDs,
核武器
nukes.
得有人阻止他
Someone has to stop him.
噢 这是我们的工作
Well, that's what we do.
我们去那个普什么的地方 做该做的事
We go out to Chiapep and we do our thing.
该做的事
Our thing?
对
Yeah.
去干掉那些坏蛋
We go out there and kill a lot of scumbags.
怎么 你有更好的计划
What? You got something better to do?
行了 来吧                        lovelzy残天 制作
All right. Pull it.
你不会哭吧
You're not gonna cry, are you?
你拔就是了
Just pull it.
有时候哭一哭更健康 杰克
Everybody needs a good cry once in a while, Jack.
- 别不好意思 - 快拔
- Don't be ashamed. - Pull it.
还记得那次
You remember that time when
你和拉尔·菲莫斯去帮人家油漆房子吗
you and Ralphie Mauser were gonna have that house-painting job?
你的手指被梯子夹到
Got your finger caught in the ladder,
回来哭了五六天
you cried for about five, six days.
快动手 约翰
John, just pull it!
- 好吧 - 快点
- All right. - Come on.
数到三 来了
On three. Here you go.
一 二
One, two...
(GRUNTS)
我的上帝啊
Good God.
天呐
Jesus.
你上一次打破伤风针是什么时候
When was the last time you had a tetanus shot?
感觉怎么样
You all right?
没事
Yeah.
我们得弄辆车
We need a car.
好小子
Atta boy.
该干活了
Back to work.
嗨 专家 锁开得怎么样了
Hey, Watergate, how's that lock coming?
就快开了
Almost there.
来 试试这个
Here, try these.
快点
Come on.
你偷东西 行啊 真有你的 约翰
Oh, stealing. That's nice. Real nice, John.
是啊 我都被提名最佳父亲了
Yeah, I'm up for the Father of the Year award.
喔
Whoa.
(JACK LAUGHS)
不错啊
All right.
你怎么知道车里有这么多枪
How'd you know all of these guns were gonna be here?
这是车臣人爱来的地方
It's a Chechen hangout.
老板不许他们带枪进店
Owner doesn't like guns in the club,
所以他们把枪留在车里
so these bozos leave them in their cars.
我这三年不是白待的
You learn a lot in three years.
行啊
Yeah.
你在睡觉？
You sleeping?
是的
I was.
Jet-lag .
Jeez，记得我们最后一次在同一部车是什么时候吗？
Jeez, when was the last time
we were in a car together?
从Trenton开车回家。
Drive home from Trenton .
因为你的武器控告，我必须去保释你
I had to bail you out for that
weapons charge.
真的？
Yeah?
不，那是一个武器的事情，不是吗？
No, it was the fire thing ,
right?
是当你放好在South Philly的武器？
When you set South Philly
on fire, you mean?
(LAUGHING)
我必须抵押了我们的房子才能保释你
We had to take out a second
mortgage on the house
to make your bail .
噢，真是不好意思
Yeah , I'm sorry about that.
真是有趣
It was funny.
(LAUGHS)
(SIGHS)
我说 我们真的要去切尔诺贝利
Are we really going to Chernobyl?
对啊
Yeah.
就是那个
The Chernobyl.
那个发生过核泄漏的地方
The radioactive joint? Meltdown?
对 就是那儿
That's the one.
不是瑞士的那个切尔诺贝利吗
It's not the Chernobyl in Switzerland, right?
那个 雪花纷飞的滑雪胜地
With all the skiing and the snow and everything?
你是说格勒诺布尔
You mean Grenoble?
不 抱歉 不是要去法国的格勒诺布尔
No, sorry, we're not going to Grenoble.
艾迪·考林斯的孩子去年带他去度假
Eddie Collins's kid took him on vacation last year.
他们去了布卡拉顿
They went down to Boca.
是吗
Oh, yeah?
在赛马场玩了四天
Spent four days at the track.
不错啊
Well, that's nice.
那才叫放松
That's relaxing.
噢 是啊 那当然
Oh, yeah. Sure.
为啥我们去切尔诺贝利
We have to go to Chernobyl?
呃 真不好意思
Yeah, sorry about that.
那边已经没有辐射污染了吗
But all the radioactive stuff is out, right?
你还记得这里吗 爸爸
Is it as you remember, papa?
我不想回忆
I don't want to remember.
老顽固
Tough.
文件
The file...
就在保险库里
...is in the inner vault.
真感人 快走吧
Very touching. Let's move.
是哪个
Which one is it?
快走吧 老山羊
Get moving, old goat.
只要上点油漆 除除草就可以住人了
Couple of fresh coats of paint and a weedwacker and it's good to go.
知道吗 一开始他们全盘否认事实
You know, at first, they denied anything even happened.
第二天还办了场儿童游行来证明
Held a children's parade the next day to prove it.
24小时后 这儿的5万居民全部被疏散
24 hours later, 50,000 residents were evacuated.
再也没有回来
Never came back.
他们一进保险库 科马洛夫就没命了
As soon as they get in that vault, Komarov's a dead man.
是啊
All right.
你有计划吗
You got a plan?
没有
Not really.
我们就看情况
I kind of thought we'd just wing it.
见机行事 即兴发挥吧 冲进去 猛开枪 打到哪儿算哪儿
You know,run in, guns blazing, making shit up as we go.
- 好啊 - 对
- Yeah? - Yeah.
这是什么 老古董
What is this? A pirate gun?
对 是挺老的
Yeah. It's old school, man.
就像你
Like you, right?
对 就像我
Yeah, like me.
有时间 我要跟你好好谈谈
One of these days, I'm gonna have a long talk with you.
听着 杰克
Look, Jack,
很遗憾你的搭档死了
I'm sorry your partner got killed.
抱歉破坏了你们的计划 我不是故意的 真的
I'm sorry I fucked up your day. That wasn't my plan.
我给你惹了麻烦
I caused you problems.
我来 不是想给你添乱的
You know, I came here for something else.
虽然碰上一大堆破事
And all that other bullshit. I mean,
可我很开心
I had a pretty good day.
跟你到处跑 挺好玩的
It's fun, running around with you.
见到你很开心
It's good to see you.
我爱你 儿子
I love you, boy.
我也爱你
You, too.
我会罩着你的
I want you to know I got your back.
我也会
I got yours, too.
行了 我们去干掉这些混蛋
All right. Let's go kill some motherfuckers.
钥匙
Key.
(LOCK DISENGAGES)
(RUMBLING)
行了 这到底在搞什么
Okay, what the fuck is this?
我的耐心是有限度的 文件最好在里面
I'm losing my patience. The fucking file better be here.
辐射在这个房间里累积了几十年
Radiation has been pooling in this room for decades.
(IRINA LAUGHS)
亲爱的老爸 你太小看我们了
You've underestimated us, Daddy dearest.
把它搬进来
Bring it in!
好样的
Atta boy.
过来 过来
Come on! Come on!
这是化合物274 它能中和辐射 相信我
Compound 27-4. It neutralizes radiation, trust me.
(MEN CHATTERING IN RUSSIAN)
(BEEPING)
安全了 可以脱掉防护服了
All clear. We can ditch the suits.
这是什么鬼东西
The hell is that?
这是价值10亿欧元的浓缩铀
One billion euros worth of enriched uranium.
什么
What?
不用担心 它在这种状态下很稳定
Don't worry, it's stable in this form.
去拿文件
File!
伊莲娜 少废话
Irina, cut the crap, please.
这儿没人关心铀的事 文件在哪儿
No one here is speaking about uranium. Where's the file?
(COCKS GUN)
别兜圈子了 文件在哪儿
No more games, where is the file?
这已经不关你的事了
That's no longer your concern.
(EXHALES EXCITEDLY)
宝贝
Sunshine...
干得漂亮
...you did well.
我说过
I told you...
有志者事竟成
...everything would work out.
到爸爸这儿来
Come to papa.
爸爸 你真是个天才
Pap, you're a genius.
我知道
I know.
装运吧
Load it up.
比嘎斯
Pegasus?
收到吗
Do you copy?
(PEGASUS RESPONDS IN RUSSIAN)
(WORKERS CHATTERING
IN RUSSIAN)
装个文件要这么大的车
A lot of hardware for a file.
五分钟后可以起飞
Wheels up in five minutes.
很好
Perfect.
枪给你 长官
Here you go, sir.
装运完毕 直升机归你了
Team extraction completed. She's all yours.
很好
Good.
(BEEPS)
(LINE RINGING)
(CELL PHONE RINGING)
你进去了吗
Are you inside?
是的 维克多
Yes, yes, Viktor.
我进来了
I'm inside.
尤里
Yuri?
你很惊讶吧
You surprised?
我现在就在所有一切开始的地方
I'm in the same place where it all started...
在你背叛我之前
...before you betrayed me.
我还记得
Remember...
你曾经承诺还给我原来的生活
...you promised to give me my life back.
你已经做到了
You gave it back to me.
为表谢意
I thank you for that.
现在
And now...
我要你的命
...I'm going to take yours.
(CHOKING)
(NECK SNAPS)
静电4号 我们准备起飞
Static 4, we are ready for take off.
静电4号 收到没有
Static 4, do you copy?
Yuri !
Yuri .
那个跳舞的呢
Where's the dancer?
你没事吧 你受伤了
You okay? You hurt?
没有
No.
我 我很好
I'm good.
(COUGHS)
我没事 我没事
I'm all right.
箱子装的是什么
What's in these boxes?
谢天谢地 你来了
Thank God you're here, Jack.
我们得走了
We have to leave.
他们随时会回来
They're coming back any minute.
我去 我去拿文件
Just let me get the file.
箱子里装了什么
What's in the boxes?
这是铀235
It's U-235.
武器级的铀
Weapons-grade uranium.
这是防护箱
Armored cases.
(COUGHS)
造炸弹的
The bomb kind?
对 就是那种
Yeah, the bomb kind.
先别急着走 伙计
Not so fast, Eddie.
你疯了吗
Are you crazy?
对 有一点儿
Yeah, a little bit.
我去拿文件
I'm getting the file.
不 你不是
No. No, you're not.
钥匙 是你保险库的
The key. It's your vault, isn't it, Yuri?
什么 不 不 我
What? No. No, I...
这些是你放在这儿的吧
You put this shit in here, right?
什么 不是
What? No.
对吗
Right?
我不知道这事
I didn't know, Jack.
(COUGHS)
地上是那个跳舞的
Is that the dancer down there?
你在胡说什么
What are you talking about?
那家伙死了怪可惜的
That's a tough break for a good athlete.
杰克 你了解我
Jack, you know me.
(KOMAROV SPEAKING RUSSIAN)
是啊 我了解你
Yeah, I know you. I know you.
可我更了解他
I know him better.
根本就没什么文件 对吗
Never was a file, was there, Yuri?
当然没有文件
Of course there was no file.
那只不过 是个诱饵
It was simply bait.
我要的东西在这个保险库里
What I needed was in this vault.
只有查克林有能力
Chagarin was the only one with enough
把我从监狱里弄出来
power and influence to get me out of jail.
我利用了他
I used him.
也利用了你
I used you.
都是为了钱
It's about money.
哪次不是为了钱
When's it not about money?
你想逮捕我
You want to arrest me?
这里不是你的辖区吧 麦克莱恩警探 对吗
You're out of your jurisdiction, Detective McClane, aren't you?
这个问题用不着你操心
I wouldn't worry too much about being arrested.
因为我儿子
See, my boy
是中情局的
is in the CIA.
可以先斩后奏
No phone call.
他是间谍
Spy shit.
噢 该死的美国人 觉得自己很聪明吗
Goddamn Americans. You think you're so smart.
我没那么聪明 我是来度假的
No, I'm not that smart. I'm just on vacation.
我儿子
My boy here,
他会好好教训你的
he gonna put a whooping on you.
(GRUNTS)
快走
Move!
跟你女儿说再见吧 混蛋
You can say goodbye to your daughter, you dumbwit fuck.
你的宝贝在哪儿呢
Where's your little Soltschanitsa?
见鬼 该死的
Shit! God damn it!
见鬼
Shit!
(PANTING)
伊莲娜 我去楼顶
Irina, I'm going to the roof...
楼顶
The roof!
杰克
Jack!
调到91频道
Set at 91.
动力系统
Power plant?
准备就绪
All good to go.
起飞
Let's go!
厉害啊
Subtle.
他的手雷是用什么做的
What the hell is in those goddamn grenades?
去抓他
Go get him!
我去搞定直升机
I'm going to the helicopter!
瓦蒂姆 去机尾看看
Vadim, watch the tail.
收到 高度120米
Copy. You are at 120 meters...
高度115米
...115 meters...
楼顶有轻武器交火
There is small arms fire coming from the roof.
我们有客人了
We have a guest.
去机尾看看
Watch the tail for me there.
快过来
Come on!
过来 快
Come on, hurry!
瓦蒂姆 给我接通发射控制器
Vadim, give me firing control now...
正在接通
Engaging!
(HELICOPTER WEAPONS WHIRRING)
杰克
Jack!
干掉他
Shoot him!
愿意效劳 爸爸
With pleasure, papa.
我可是来度假的
I'm on fucking vacation!
瓦蒂姆 他在那儿 我看到他了
Vadim! He is there! I see him!
为孩子拼老命了
The shit we do for our kids.
跟我斗 玩死你
Yippee ki-yay, motherfucker.
怎么回事
What happened?
飞机失去平衡
CG's shifted...
前进速度已经调到最大
I've got full forward cyclic.
我要失去控制了
I can't hold it.
我的天呐
Jesus Christ!
干得好
Well done,
超级间谍
Mr. Super-spy.
可惜你爸没法活着看到你升官了
What a shame your father won't be alive to see you promoted.
(LAUGHING)
你也一样
Neither will you.
(SCREAMS)
嗨 杰克
Hey! Jack!
坚持住 约翰
Hang on, John!
(YELLS)
(SHOUTING IN RUSSIAN)
约翰
John!
快走
Come on!
我们没有弹药了
We're out of ammunition!
妈的
Shit.
狗杂种
Bastards.
你他妈的要干什么
What the hell are you doing?
我来为你报仇 爸爸
This is for you, papa.
John !
(GASPING)
Dad !
我在这儿
Right here.
你刚才叫我爸爸
Did you just call me Dad?
没有
No.
我想也是
I didn't think so.
你幻听了
You're hearing things.
耳朵进水了吧
You got swimmer's ear.
我们不会多长出个手臂什么的吧
We're not gonna grow any third arms or anything, are we?
不会
No.
不过你可能会秃头
You might lose your hair.
你就笑吧
Laugh it up, kid.
再过五年你也会这样
This is you, five years from now.
那是雨水 没事的
It's rainwater. You'll be fine.
再说了 麦克莱恩家的人没那么容易死
Besides, it's hard to kill a McClane.
你是麦克莱恩家的人
Now you're a McClane?
对 我是麦克莱恩家的人 约翰·麦克莱恩
Yeah, I'm a McClane. John McClane.
小约翰·麦克莱恩
John McClane Junior.
噢 那你就是老约翰了
Well, that makes you a "senior."
没错
That's right.
可别忘了
Try not to forget it.
我是你爸爸
I'm your father.
你得学会尊重长辈
Have some respect for your father.
我问你件事
Let me ask you something.
是你爱找麻烦
Do you go looking for trouble
还是麻烦总是 来找你
or does it always just seem to find you?
知道吗 这么多年了
You know, after all these years,
我自己也没想明白过
I still ask myself the same question.
lovelzy残天 制作
真是蛋碎了一地工作